Astrid Countee, M.A.

832-477-3298 astridwcountee@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/astridcountee/

https://github.com/astridw

I am a problem solver, futuristic thinker and innovative leader. My keen ability to strategize and understand data in context gives me unique insight to problems, solutions, and team work. I plan to use my technical, research and project management skills in a web development position.

EDUCATION

The Iron Yard Academy—Programming boot-camp where I am currently learning web development languages and software development principles. Graduated December 2014.

University of Houston – MA Applied Anthropology: training in ethnographic analysis, field methods, cultural theory, and statistics. Invited to health fairs in the Houston area to speak on my thesis topic, chronic disease, in 2013.

Baylor University – BA Psychology with emphasis on cognition

Coursework Included: neuroscience, society and culture, linguistics, statistics, research, coordinator for psychological experiments

SOFTWARE SKILLS AND LANGUAGES

- Ruby
- Ruby on Rails
- HTML, CSS, Sass
- JavaScript
- Git, Github
- Responsive Web Design
- Ajax
- Bootstrap, Middleman

- Prv
- JQuery
- JSON APIs, REST
- Unit Testing
- UX/UI Design
- Heroku
- Agile Development
- AWS

- SQL
- SSMS
- Excel
- Access
- R
- Project Management Rapid Assessment

WORK EXPERIENCE

Business Data Analyst—Technical Training and Development

Williams Company

September 2013- July 2014

- Developed interactive charts visualizing data for fortune 200 Senior VPs
- Created Williams first ever Technical Training Database to track company metrics across North America
- Contributed to design team for internal website, participated in usability testing of eLearning courses

Astrid Countee, M.A.

832-477-3298 astridwcountee@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/astridcountee/ https://github.com/astridw

Production Data Supervisor

TGS Geophysical Company

October 2012 – September 2013

- 1st supervisor for this product, improved data warehousing, managed software development life cycle
- Designed and co-created UI for analyst team that cut product delivery time by 50%
- Grew QA team by 200% within 6 months
- Shortened turnaround for customers by 70% by developing close relationships with sales, marketing, customer support and development team
- 1st multi-million dollar contract for this product

Jr. Operations Data Analyst

TGS Geophysical Company

March 2011 - September 2012

- 1st analyst for new ground breaking product
- Set the standard for product QA and usability testing
- Increased customer subscriptions by 100%

Upstream Well Data Supervisor

TGS Geophysical Company

January 2006 - March 2011

- Strategically managed between 50 and 70 employees and coordinators
- Increased monthly output while cutting overtime by 80% by implementing strategic workflows
- Grew staff by 20% and trained all current staff while maintaining and exceeding monthly goals
- Created mentorship program to all staff members to accelerate their careers

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Host of New Books in Anthropology, New Books Network

-I find and interview authors of recently published books related to the anthropology

Trainee, MD Anderson Cancer Center: CRMH (Center for Research in Minority Health)

-I participated in research and analysis of survey data for health disparities research using SPSS. During my time there I also contributed to conferences on health disparities in Texas.

Rails Girls Coach, Rails Girls Houston

-coached girls in a weekend workshop to create web applications with ruby on rails